- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[Hawaiian music]
[夏威夷音乐]
*
- I'm ready.
I'm ready.
- 我准备好了。
我准备好了。
Ready to steal the Krabby Patty
secret formula.
准备偷走蟹黄饼
秘密配方。
Prepare to initiate plan
number...hmm...
准备启动计划
数……嗯……
number--what's the number?
号码——号码是多少？
Oh well, who cares?
哦，好吧，谁在乎呢？
- Good question.
- 好问题。
- Say wha?
- 说什么？
- I said, good luck.
- 我说，祝你好运。
- That formula will be mine.
- 那个公式将是我的。
Out of my way, pinheads.
别挡我的路，笨蛋。
Move it.
Move it. Move it.
移动它。
移动它。移动它。
Hey there, Schnozzola.
嘿，施诺佐拉。
I'm about to show you the
advantage of not having a nose.
我要向你展示
优点是没有鼻子。
Say hello to...
Mr. Stinky!
向...问好
臭先生！
[together]
What is that? A kitty cat?
[一起]
那是什么？一只小猫？
Oh, it's so cute.
It's adorable.
哦，真可爱。
很可爱。
- That's right, everyone,
gather in real close.
- 没错，大家，
真正近距离地聚集在一起。
Time to trigger the stench.
是时候触发恶臭了。
Yoink.
哟因克。
[bee buzzing]
[蜜蜂嗡嗡声]
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
[farts]
[放屁]
[together]
Ahh! I'll never breathe again.
[一起]
啊！我再也无法呼吸了
- Ahhhhhhh!
- 啊啊啊啊！
- [gasping]
- [喘气]
- Ahh!
- 啊！
- Huh?
- 啊？
No.
No, no, no, no.
不。
不，不，不，不。
No,
not the patties!
不，
不是肉饼！
I'll save you.
我会救你的。
[sniffs]
[嗅嗅]
[groans]
[呻吟]
- What's all the racket out
here?
- 到底是怎么回事？
在这里？
[sniffing]
[嗅嗅]
[together]
Ahhh!
[一起]
啊啊！
- Get it off!
Get it off of me!
- 把它取下来！
把它从我身上拿开！
- Mr. Krabs,
are you all right?
- 蟹老板先生，
你还好吗？
What happened?
- I don't know.
发生了什么？
- 我不知道。
Me eyes were burning.
我的眼睛在燃烧。
All I saw was a little eyeball
and a pair of antenna
我只看到一个小眼球
和一对天线
and...Plankton!
还有……浮游生物！
He's still in there,
alone, with me secret formula.
他还在里面，
独自一人，和我一起的秘密配方。
He could be doing
anything with it.
他可能正在做
任何与它有关的东西。
He could be reading it.
他可能正在读它。
Gimme yer hand, boy-o.
把你的手给我，男孩。
I need to borrow this.
我需要借这个。
Okay,
I'm going in.
好吧，
我要进去了。
- Good luck, Mr. Krabs.
- 祝你好运，蟹老板。
- Hmm.
- 唔。
Hmm, mm-mm-mm-mm-mm-mm.
嗯，毫米-毫米-毫米-毫米-毫米-毫米。
Mm?
毫米？
Why, you little--
为什么，你这个小——
- I hope you like percussion,
Eugene.
- 我希望你喜欢打击乐，
尤金.
Because these drumsticks really
go bongo.
因为这些鸡腿真的
去邦戈吧。
[laughs]
[笑]
[loud explosion]
[爆炸声]
Ahh.
啊。
What?
The old safe-in-a-safe routine?
什么？
旧的安全套惯例？
- Here's another routine:
- 这是另一个例程：
you're the
meat in me knuckle sandwich.
你是
我的指关节三明治里有肉。
- I'm not hungry.
- 我不饿。
- Bleh.
- 布莱赫。
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
- Yes, sir.
I see the problem.
- 是的，先生。
我看到了问题所在。
- Yeeeooow!
- 耶哦！
[militaristic music]
[军国主义音乐]
*
[together]
Yay! Hooray! Whoo-hoo!
[一起]
耶！万岁！呼呼！
- [farts]
- [放屁]
[together]
Ahh!
[一起]
啊！
- Oooh, that was too close,
m'lad.
- 哦，那太近了，
小伙子。
Three more safes and he would
have had me secret formula.
再多三个保险箱他就会
有我的秘密配方。
Looks like I'm gonna have to
beef up security around here.
看来我得
加强这里的安全。
I'm gonna need you to do me a
big favor, laddie.
我需要你帮我做一个
帮个大忙，小伙子。
Take this home with you and hide
it
把这个带回家藏起来
它
while I reevaluate
my security situation.
当我重新评估时
我的安全状况。
- Whoa-oh, oh, oh, oh.
- 哇哦，哦，哦，哦。
But, Mr. Krabs, how do you know
it will be safe
但是，蟹老板，你怎么知道
会很安全的
from Plankton at my house?
来自我家的浮游生物？
- Pe-shaw, he'll think it's
still here.
- Pe-shaw，他会认为这是
还在这里。
His tiny brain is incapable of
the kind of abstract thinking
他的小脑袋无法
那种抽象思维
that is required for reflection
这是反思所需要的
or thoughtful reasoning and
deduction.
或深思熟虑的推理和
扣除。
He cannot ruminate.
他无法反省。
He cannot divine the
hypothesis.
他无法占卜
假设。
He's a tired clown.
他是一个疲惫的小丑。
He'll never know it's in your
house.
他永远不会知道它在你的里面
房子。
- Oh, you're right, Professor
Krab-Face.
- 哦，你说得对，教授
螃蟹脸。
I'm much too simpleminded to
look there.
我太简单了
看看那里。
[cackling]
[咯咯笑]
[jazzy suspenseful music]
【爵士悬疑音乐】
*
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
- Hey, there.
- 嘿。
- Ahh!
- 啊！
- Pleasant night, eh, SpongeBob?
- 愉快的夜晚，嗯，海绵宝宝？
- Oh, uh...yes.
- 哦，呃...是的。
It's a very...nighty...night for
a walkie.
这是一个非常...夜晚...的夜晚
步话机。
- Ain't that the truth.
- 这不是事实吗？
Hey, nothing
gets past you.
嘿，没什么
超越你。
One could say you
have the "formula" for honesty.
有人可以说你
有诚实的“公式”。
- Uh, yeah, one could say that,
I guess.
- 呃，是的，有人可以这么说，
我猜。
Anyway, I gotta go wash
my formula--hair!
无论如何，我得去洗漱了
我的公式——头发！
Hair!
I gotta go wash my hair!
头发！
我得去洗头了！
Uh...good night, Plankton.
呃……晚安，浮游生物。
- Yeah, gotta keep that hair
clean...and in a safe place.
- 是的，必须保留那头发
干净……并且在安全的地方。
- Uh, okay, bye.
- 呃，好吧，再见。
- Now, remember, Gary.
- 现在，记住，加里。
I'm entrusting
you with the secret formula.
我委托
你用秘密公式。
- Meow.
- Stay sharp, Gary.
- 喵。
- 保持敏锐，加里。
Don't let anyone inside.
不要让任何人进来。
- Meow.
- Bye, Gary.
- 喵。
- 再见，加里。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
- [cackling]
- [咯咯笑]
[knock at door]
[敲门]
- Why, hey, there, little fella.
- 为什么，嘿，那里，小家伙。
Is SpongeBob--I mean--
your master at home?
海绵宝宝是——我是说——
你家主人？
Uh, perhaps I could just come
inside for a minute
呃，也许我可以来
里面一分钟
and demonstrate our fine snail
products:
并展示我们的精美蜗牛
产品：
shell polish, slime deodorant,
chew toys,
贝壳抛光剂、粘液除臭剂、
咀嚼玩具，
My leg!
我的腿！
Your friends won't tell you
this,
你的朋友不会告诉你
这个，
but you can really use the slime
deodorant, smelly.
但你真的可以使用史莱姆
除臭剂，臭。
[doorbell rings]
[门铃响]
- Hello, s...
[clears throat]
- 你好，是...
[清嗓子]
Hello, sir.
你好先生。
I'm selling Sweetie
Patrol cookies.
我要卖甜甜
巡逻饼干。
We have a lovely assortment of
fungi and algae flavors.
我们有各种各样的可爱的
真菌和藻类的味道。
How many delicious boxes can
I put you down for?
能吃多少盒好吃的
我贬低你是为了什么？
If you order
ten boxes, I'll qualify for my
如果您订购
十盒，我就有资格获得我的
Bottom Dweller Badge.
底层居民徽章。
If you order 100 boxes,
I'll get my Bling Bling Badge.
如果您订购 100 盒，
我会得到我的 Bling Bling 徽章。
You know, you should
hide these from your roommate.
你知道，你应该
对你的室友隐藏这些。
She'll eat all of them.
她会把它们全部吃掉。
If you show me your best hiding
place, I'd be happy to help.
如果你向我展示你最好的隐藏
的地方，我很乐意提供帮助。
- Meow, meow!
- 喵，喵！
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
[loud explosion]
[爆炸声]
Ehhh, note to self:
呃，自我提醒：
nitroglycerine is not a
substitute
硝化甘油不是
替代品
for vanilla extract.
用于香草精。
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
Meow?
喵？
[growling]
[咆哮]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
I forgot how much I
hate pineapple.
我忘记了我是多少
讨厌菠萝。
- [mumbling]
- [咕哝]
- Ehh.
- 呃。
- [mumbling]
- [咕哝]
- [munching]
- [咀嚼]
Hey, this snail litter tastes
better than pineapple.
嘿，这蜗牛窝有味道
比菠萝好。
Now, where is
that secret formula?
现在，在哪里
那个秘密配方？
Where is it?
它在哪里？
Gotta be
here somewhere.
一定是
这里某处。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Nothin' in there.
Ooh, look at that.
里面什么也没有。
哦，看看那个。
Mm-hmm.
嗯嗯。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Hello.
[echoing]
你好。
[回声]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Where the barnacles is it?
藤壶在哪里？
Gah!
嘎！
Where is it?
它在哪里？
I know you're in here.
我知道你在这儿。
You're not fooling anybody.
你没有欺骗任何人。
I went to college.
我上大学了。
Nope. Nope. Nope.
没有。没有。没有。
[dropper whistles]
[滴管哨声]
Hmm.
唔。
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
[loud thump]
[重击声]
- Whew.
- 呼。
[cackles]
[咯咯笑]
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
- Meow?
- 喵？
Ohh-ohh.
哦哦。
- Ehh? Mm-hmm. Uh-huh.
- 呃？嗯嗯。嗯嗯。
Wah! Wah!
哇！哇！
Ahh!
啊！
Augh! Oof! Ahh-ahh-ahh-ahh!
Ugh! Ahh-ahh-ahh!
啊啊！钱币！啊啊啊啊啊啊！
啊!啊啊啊啊！
- [snickers]
- [窃笑]
- Ahh!
- 啊！
Ooh!
哦！
Ahh! Augh!
啊！啊啊！
Eh, eh, eh...augh!
诶诶诶……哎呀！
Ehh, ehh, ehh, augh!
呃呃呃呃！
[vacuum whirring]
[真空呼呼]
- Ooh.
[grunting]
- 哦。
[咕噜声]
All right, snail,
let's go.
好吧，蜗牛，
我们走吧。
Just you and me.
只有你和我。
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
- Put 'em up.
Put 'em up.
- 把它们放起来。
把它们放起来。
Ooh! Oh! Ooh! Oh! Ahh!
哦！哦！哦！哦！啊！
- Meow!
- 喵！
- Huh?
- 啊？
Of course.
当然。
What a fool I've been.
我真是个傻瓜。
- SpongeBob's hidden the secret
formula inside Gary's shell.
- 海绵宝宝隐藏了秘密
加里壳内的公式。
Sheesh, this place is
disgusting.
谢什，这个地方是
恶心的。
I bet it reeks.
我打赌它一定很臭。
Good thing I don't
have a nose.
还好我不
有鼻子。
Ay-yi-yi.
艾依依。
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh!
啊啊啊啊啊啊啊啊啊！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Ahh!
啊！
- Gary, I'm home.
- 加里，我回来了。
[gasps]
[喘气]
What happened here?
这里发生了什么？
Oh, my first Krabby
Patty.
哦，我的第一个蟹蟹
帕蒂。
I had it bronzed.
我把它晒成了古铜色。
Oh, and I was gonna give that
to my grandchildren.
哦，我本来打算给的
给我的孙子们。
Ahh, my Mermaid Man collectable
underpants.
啊啊，我的美人鱼男人收藏品
内裤。
Oh, I could have worn them
1,000 more times.
哦，我本来可以穿它们
再重复1000次。
[gasps]
My glass of water.
[喘气]
我的一杯水。
I was gonna drink that.
我正想喝那个。
Oh,
the Krabby Patty formula.
哦，
蟹黄饼配方。
Oh, it's safe,
and right where I left it.
哦，安全了，
就在我离开的地方。
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
- Gary, did you do this?
- 加里，这是你做的吗？
What's the matter, Gary?
怎么了，加里？
Something wrong with your shell?
- Meow.
你的外壳有问题吗？
- 喵。
- Something's not right, Gary.
- 有点不对劲，加里。
I better get you to the vet.
我最好带你去看兽医。
- Meow.
- 喵。
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
Whoa-oh, ehh-ehh.
哇哦，呃呃。
Ha,
I lost him.
哈，
我失去了他。
And now I'm lost.
现在我迷路了。
Ahhhhhhhh!
啊啊啊啊！
Ehh...my head.
呃……我的头。
Ooh, I must be in the
center of the shell.
哦，我一定是在
壳的中心。
What's that?
This is it.
那是什么？
就是这样。
Just like I thought.
就像我想的那样。
It was hidden here all the time.
它一直隐藏在这里。
The
secret Krabby Patty formula.
的
秘制蟹黄派配方。
It's beautiful.
很美丽。
The heavenly light.
天上的光。
I always knew I'd see it once
I'd gotten the formula.
我一直都知道我会看到它一次
我已经得到了公式。
Let me bask in it's glory.
让我沐浴在它的荣耀之中吧。
- Well, that's odd.
Who's that?
- 嗯，这很奇怪。
那是谁？
- Hey, it's Plankton.
- 嘿，这是浮游生物。
- What's he got there?
- 他那里有什么？
- Looks like one of my old
grocery lists.
- 看起来像我的旧人之一
杂货清单。
- I don't know how he got in
there,
- 我不知道他是怎么进来的
在那里，
but the gasses inside this shell
但是这个壳里面的气体
are making the little guy
hallucinate.
正在制作小家伙
产生幻觉。
He would have smelled the gasses
if he had a nose,
他会闻到气体的味道
如果他有鼻子的话
like most good-hearted people
像大多数好心人一样
[sniffs]
[嗅嗅]
- Ha-ha.
I got it!
- 哈哈。
我得到了它！
I got it!
I finally got the formula!
我终于得到公式了！
It's mine! It's mine! It's mine!
It's mine!
这是我的！这是我的！这是我的！
这是我的！
Open the sparkling apple
juice, Karen!
打开闪闪发光的苹果
果汁，凯伦！
Daddy's bringing the
bacon home!
爸爸带来了
培根回家！
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Wow!
呼呼呼呼！
哇！